Hello welcome my name is Julio Nutt and I am a master instructor of the Jim McLean Golf School in Miami, Florida.
In this clip I am going to talk about a great drill that is really going to help you to shift your weight forward.
In golf you have got to learn to shift your weight forward in order to hit the ball and transfer your weight into your left side.
But many amateurs when hitting the ball they hang to the right side, they get their arms really close and tight to their bodies and they have a lot of difficulty transferring their weight into their left side.
Just using a shaft would be a great drill to use because when we're throwing something forward we're throwing a Frisbee, if we're throwing a ball the natural motion is to throw the weight with it.
So right now I'm not going to think about hitting the golf ball, I'm going to think about throwing the shaft.
So I'm going to get in my golf position and as I swing I am going to let the shot go as hard as I can and that is really going to help me develop the habit of throwing my weight.
That is a great tip that I give to a lot of my students.
When hitting the ball think about throwing the club and that is going to generate extension and weight transfer.
This is Julio Nutt at the Jim McLean Golf School.